You may be wondering how to come up with alpha factors and trading strategies.
你也许想知道 如何提出 alpha 因子和交易策略？
Some sources of inspiration,
灵感来源有很多
maybe reading financial news,
例如阅读财经新闻
observing the markets for curious behavior,
观察市场的奇怪行为
studying the methods of famous investors both
研究任意知名投资者或量化分析师的方法
discretionary and want or talking to industry practitioners.
或者咨询从业者
We'll explore academic research papers as a source for
我们将在这节课的剩余部分以及下节课
alpha factor ideas through the remainder of this lesson and in the next lesson.
研究学术论文 并从中发现 alpha 因子理念
It's important to understand a key point before we do this.
在开始学习之前 需要注意的是
We should not expect to get
我们不能期待
strong production-ready alphas ''as is'' from academic papers.
会从学术论文中发现可以直接应用的强 alpha 信号
Why not? Because the very act of publication which makes the paper
为何呢？因为公布论文之后
publicly available also diffuses this information into the market.
会在市场中稀释这些 alpha 信息
As participants adopt the trading strategy,
当市场参与者采用这些交易策略后
the strength of the effect is diffused.
效果就被稀释了
Why then do we look at academic papers at all?
那为何还要研究学术论文呢？
For four reasons.
原因有四个
First, these papers can spur idea generation for us to create derivative works.
首先 这些论文可以激发我们继续创作的灵感
Second, the work conserve as baseline factors to compare with our own alpha generation.
其次 这些成果可以作为基准因子来与我们自己生成的 alpha 进行比较
Third, we can learn how professional full-time
第三条 我们可以了解全职专业研究员
researchers approach problems and validate their findings.
如何解决问题以及验证他们的研究结果
Fourth, perhaps we can learn about new sources of data or novel ways to work with data.
第四条 也许我们可以发现新的数据来源或处理数据的新方式
Academic research can be published in general interests economic journals,
学术研究会发表在一般的经济期刊中
investment focused journals, or open source journals.
投资类期刊中或开源期刊中
General interest journals and investment focused journals both
一般的期刊和投资类期刊
require peer review and require a paid subscription.
都需要同行评审和付费订阅
Open source repositories usually include working papers that
开源资料库通常包含
have not yet been peer reviewed and are also free.
尚未同行评审的研究中论文 并且是免费的
Open source repositories for research papers include,
研究论文开源资料库包括
SSRN and the archive.
SSRN 及 archive
One benefit to using open source journals is that there's
使用开源期刊的一个优势是
a broader selection of papers and their ideas more recent,
可以选择的论文更多 并且他们的理念更新
since peer review is a process that takes time.
因为同行评审需要时间
It helps to figure out which other papers cite a particular article,
了解其他论文引用的特定文章也有帮助
to see how other researchers attempted to
可以看看其他研究人员
replicate critique or improve upon the original idea.
如何重现评论文章或改进原始理念
Once you've found some papers of interests,
找到感兴趣的论文后
scan the abstract and find out if the data use is accessible to you.
浏览下摘要并看看你能否获得论文中用到的数据
Focus on papers for which the data is
专注于能获得相关数据的论文
accessible so that you may try to replicate their work.
这样你也能重现他们的成果
Check that the methodology could potentially be practical.
检查方法是否切实可行
Academic papers almost never include
学术论文几乎不会直接考虑
real-world constraints like transaction costs or liquidity directly.
现实中的约束条件 例如交易成本或流动性
You need to make a judgment quickly if you think adding
你需要快速判断
these constraints will completely invalidate the ideas presented.
添加这些约束条件后是否完全使论文阐述的理念变得无效
Some papers include these aspects in a roundabout way.
某些论文会迂回地考虑这些约束条件
They conducted Turnover Analysis or they choose
他们会进行周转率分析
a stock universe that includes more illiquid stocks.
或向股票池中添加流动性更差的股票
Some examples of impractical methods may
一些不切实际的方法示例包括
include choosing a large universe of say 8,000 stocks,
股票池很大 例如包括 8,000 支股票
in which most of the factor returns are derived from
大多数因子收益率都来自
a subset of the small and micro cap stocks.
一小部分小盘股
Remember that small and micro cap stocks are less liquid and factors that
小盘股的流动性更低
rely on illiquid stocks may be difficult to implement in practice.
依赖于低流动性股票的因子难以实施
Note that the process of finding academic papers, studying papers,
注意 发现学术论文 研究论文
implementing the papers and then evaluating them
实施论文理念 然后进行评估这一流程
is a very important skill to have as a quantitative researcher.
是量化研究员应该掌握的很重要技能
We hope to walk you through some of these examples,
我们希望通过几个示例
so that you will eventually have the confidence
学完这节课后
to conduct your own research after this course.
你最终有信心自己展开研究